primerica.com 2002-12-17

# Primerica Online

| 

**Primerica Privacy Notice**

**Your Privacy Is Important To Us.**

**Your Trust Is Our Priority**  

Consumer privacy is making headlines lately. With all the communication channels available today, protecting the personal information of customers has assumed a new level of concern. This pamphlet is provided to every prospective Primerica customer in an effort to assure our customers understand our information practices and their rights to direct us in the sharing of certain information.  

At Primerica, we’ve made privacy a priority since we began doing business. In fact, in addition to legal requirements, we’ve long observed our own high standards of protecting your privacy, long before this issue was newsworthy. We know our business depends on your trust and confidence, and we’ll never jeopardize that.

**Your Privacy at Primerica**

Keeping customer information secure and using it only as permitted by law and our own high standards is a top priority for all of us at Primerica, a member of the Citigroup family of companies. We care about the privacy of our customers who obtain products or services from us for personal, family or household purposes (“you”). We are providing you this Notice to help you understand the information we collect, and what information we may disclose about you. This Notice also tells you what to do if you do not want us to disclose certain personal information about you.  

While information is the cornerstone of our ability to provide superior service, our most important asset is our customers’ trust. We will limit the collection and use of customer information to the minimum we require to deliver superior service to our customers, which includes advising our customers about our products, services and other opportunities, and to administer our business. We will tell current customers in plain language, initially and at least once annually, how they may remove their names from marketing lists. At any time, customers can contact us to remove their names from such lists. We will attempt to keep customer files complete, up to date, and accurate. We will tell our customers how and where to conveniently access their information (except when we’re prohibited by law) and how to notify us about errors, which we will promptly correct.

We apply the same policies to former customers that apply to current customers. We may amend our privacy notice from time to time. As required by law, we will send our current customers our privacy notice at least annually. We will comply with your privacy choice in accordance with federal law and the privacy laws and regulations of your state. 

**Our Policies and Practices to Protect Your Personal Information**

Primerica operates through a group of companies that are managed from our headquarters in Duluth, Georgia. These companies include Primerica Financial Services, Inc., Primerica Life Insurance Company, PFS Investments Inc., Primerica Financial Services Home Mortgages, Inc. and Primerica Client Services, Inc. In this document, the Primerica group of companies are referred to collectively as “Primerica,” and are also referred to as “We,” “Us” or “Our.” The products and services Primerica sells (collectively, “products”) include insurance, mutual funds, variable annuities and loans. Primerica markets these products through its independent Representatives who typically market only those financial products authorized by Primerica. The Representatives are sending you their privacy notice in this same pamphlet, which you should read in conjunction with this Notice.

I. Information Security  
Primerica protects personal information it collects about you by maintaining physical, electronic and procedural safeguards that meet or exceed requirements of applicable law. Any affiliates and nonaffiliated third parties to whom Primerica provides your personal information must agree to follow appropriate standards of security and confidentiality. Primerica instructs its employees how to properly handle personal information. 

II. Categories of Personal Information We Collect and May Disclose   
Depending upon the product, we collect a wide variety of personal information about you and your family. Where permitted by law, we may collect:  

  * Information we receive from you on applications or other forms, such as your name, address, social security number, assets, income and beneficiaries;  

  * Information about your transactions with us, Primerica affiliates or others, such as your policy coverage, premiums, account balances and payment history;  

  * Information we receive from consumer reporting agencies, such as your creditworthiness and credit history; and  

  * Information we receive from affiliates and nonaffiliated third parties, including information Primerica receives from Representatives, in connection with marketing our products.   

Generally, we collect and may disclose this information in connection with processing your business and marketing products to you. As permitted by law, we may disclose all of this personal information.III. Categories of Affiliates To Whom Primerica May Disclose Personal Information  
The companies that comprise Primerica may share personal information about you amongst themselves, as well as with Primerica’s affiliates, who are the family of companies controlled by Citigroup Inc. These affiliates are in several different lines of business, including banking, property and casualty insurance, life insurance, securities, consumer finance and credit cards.  
  
IV. Categories of Nonaffiliated Third Parties To Whom We May Disclose Personal Information  
Nonaffiliated third parties are those not part of the family of companies controlled by Citigroup Inc. Representatives are nonaffiliated third parties of Primerica.  

We may disclose personal information about you to nonaffiliated third parties with your consent or at your direction. We may also disclose certain information about you without your consent to nonaffiliated third parties, as permitted by law, for purposes such as servicing or maintaining your product, processing a transaction that you request, allowing nonaffiliated third parties to perform services or marketing on our behalf, and complying with legal requirements.  

The categories of nonaffiliated third parties we disclose information to are the following:  

  * Financial services providers, such as companies engaged in banking, consumer finance, securities and insurance; and  

  * Non-financial companies, such as companies engaged in direct marketing, retailing and the selling of customer products and services.  

Additionally, we may disclose all of the information we collect about you, as described above, to nonaffiliated third parties that perform marketing or other services on our behalf or to other financial institutions with whom we have joint marketing or service agreements. We may also disclose nonpublic personal information about you to nonaffiliated third parties as permitted by law.

V. Your Ability to Opt Out of Certain Information Disclosure   
You may request that we not disclose certain personal information about you, that is, to “opt out” of disclosure:

> A. Sharing Among the Primerica Companies and with Primerica Affiliates  
>  While the law allows us to share personal information regarding your transactions and our experiences with you among ourselves, as well as with our affiliates, we will not share any other information, except to the extent sharing is permitted by law, if you have opted out as provided in this Notice.  
> 
> 
> B. Disclosure to Nonaffiliated Third Parties  
>  We will not disclose your personal information to nonaffiliated third parties if you opt out, except to the extent disclosure is permitted by law. 

To opt out, see the section below entitled, “How to Opt Out of Information Disclosure.”

VI. How to Opt Out of Information Disclosure   
We are committed to informing you about new products and services that may be useful to you and sharing information helps us do this. However, if you prefer that we not share certain personal information (except as any sharing is permitted by law), please fill out and return the attached form. Even if you do opt out, your Representative may still contact you.  

Your request to opt out of this Notice or the attached notice from the Representatives will result in your opting out under both notices. If you jointly obtain a Primerica product with others, your opt out request will also apply to them.  

Your request will remain in effect until you notify us otherwise in writing. If you have opted out previously, you need not do so again.  

If you are also a customer of other Citigroup affiliates (such as Citibank, CitiMortgage, Travelers Bank & Trust, fsb, Travelers Insurance, Salomon Smith Barney) and you receive a notice of their intent to disclose certain information about you, you will need to separately notify them if you do not want that information disclosed.

VII. Your Insurance Policy: Correcting Your Personal Information  
If you are considering the purchase of or have purchased a life insurance policy from Primerica, state insurance law may provide you with the right, except in certain circumstances, to see and copy the personal information that Primerica has about you. 

You have the right to ask Primerica to correct, amend or delete any information about you which you believe to be incorrect. If the information should be corrected, Primerica will update its files, and send the correction to anyone who received the incorrect information. If Primerica does not agree that the information is incorrect, you have the right to give Primerica a statement of what you believe to be the correct information, which Primerica will place in your file and send to anyone who received or will receive the original information. 

However, we will not send you any medical information we have received about you from a doctor or other health care provider. Instead, you should contact the doctor or health care provider directly to obtain the information you seek. In addition, information collected in connection with, or in reasonable anticipation of, a claim or civil or criminal proceeding is not subject to the rights described above. 

If you have any questions about the right of access to, or the correction of, the information in your file, please write Primerica Life at our Executive Offices located at 3120 Breckinridge Boulevard, Duluth, GA 30099-0001. Please include a copy of some type of personal identification, such as your driver’s license.

Primerica is a member of the Citigroup global family of companies, which have extended the Citigroup Privacy Promise to their customers worldwide. As a current customer of Primerica, in addition to the protections described in the above Privacy Notice required by U.S. law, you are covered by the Citigroup Privacy Promise.

**Citigroup Privacy Promise for Customers**

While information is the cornerstone of our ability to provide superior service, our most important asset is our customer's trust. Keeping customer information secure, and using it only as our customers would want us to, is a top priority for all of us at Citigroup. Here, then, is our Promise to our individual customers:

1\. We will safeguard, according to strict standards of security and confidentiality, any information our customers share with us.

2\. We will limit the collection and use of customer information to the minimum we require to deliver superior service to our customers, which includes advising our customers about our products, services and other opportunities, and to administer our business.

3\. We will permit only authorized employees, who are trained in the proper handling of customer information, to have access to that information. Employees who violate our Privacy Promise will be subject to our normal disciplinary process.

4\. We will not reveal customer information to any external organization unless we have previously informed the customer in disclosures or agreements, have been authorized by the customer or are required by law.

5\. We will always maintain control over the confidentiality of our customer information. We may, however, facilitate relevant offers from reputable companies. These companies are not permitted to retain any customer information unless the customer has specifically expressed interest in their products or services.

6\. We will tell customers in plain language, initially and at least once annually, how they may remove their names from marketing lists. At any time, customers can contact us to remove their names from such lists.

7\. Whenever we hire other organizations to provide support services, we will require them to conform to our privacy standards and to allow us to audit them for compliance.

8\. For purposes of credit reporting, verification and risk management, we will exchange information about our customers with reputable reference sources and clearinghouse services.

9\. We will not use or share — internally or externally — personally identifiable medical information for any purpose other than the underwriting or administration of a customer’s policy, claim or account, or as disclosed to the customer when the information is collected, or to which the customer consents.

10\. We will attempt to keep customer files complete, up to date, and accurate. We will tell our customers how and where to conveniently access their information (except when we’re prohibited by law) and how to notify us about errors, which we will promptly correct.

We will continuously assess ourselves to ensure that customer privacy is respected. We will conduct our business in a manner that fulfills our Promise in the many nations in which we do business.  

The Primerica Companies are dedicated to providing financial solutions for your needs. We are committed to bringing you excellent financial products and superior service. Additionally, we are committed to protecting information we may have about our customers. If you wish to verify that the information we have about you is correct, simply write us and tell us. To examine certain information we have in our files about you, send your name, policy or account number and social security number to us at: Privacy Officer, P. O. Box 2318, Duluth, GA 30096-0040.

**Your Independent Primerica Representatives’ Privacy Policy**

The Primerica companies market financial products and services through us, their independent contractor Representatives. We typically market only those financial products and services authorized for sale by Primerica. Groups of Representatives typically share offices and assist each other in the marketing and processing of Primerica products, in effect, acting as a team to market the various financial products and services (collectively, “products”) to you and to process your business.   

As Representatives, we are providing you this Notice to help you understand how we may collect information about you, the type of information we may collect, and what information we may disclose about you. This Notice also tells you what to do if you do not want us to disclose certain personal information about you. We apply the same policies to former customers that apply to current customers. We may amend our privacy policy from time to time. As required by law, we will send our current customers our most recent privacy notice at least annually. We will comply with your privacy choice in accordance with federal law and the privacy laws and regulations of your state. The Primerica companies are sending you their privacy notice in this same pamphlet, which you should read in conjunction with this Notice.

I. Information Security  
Representatives, in our independent offices, take appropriate measures to protect your personal information and require others who have access to follow appropriate standards of security and confidentiality.II. Categories of Personal Information We Collect and May Disclose  
Depending upon the product, we collect a wide variety of personal information about you and your family. Where permitted by law, we may collect:

  * Information we receive from you, such as your name, address, social security number, assets, income and beneficiaries;  

  * Information about your transactions and experiences with us, Primerica, Primerica affiliates or others, such as your policy coverage, premiums, account balances and payment history; and  

  * Information we receive from nonaffiliated third parties, such as information a Representative receives from other Representatives, from Primerica or from Primerica affiliates.  

Generally, Representatives collect and may disclose this information in connection with processing your business and marketing products to you. Although not all Representatives collect and disclose to the same extent, we may disclose all of this personal information to the extent permitted by law.III. Categories of Nonaffiliated Third Parties To Whom We May Disclose Personal Information  
We may disclose personal information about you to nonaffiliated third parties with your consent or at your direction. We may also disclose personal information about you, as permitted by law, to the following categories of nonaffiliated third parties:   

  * Primerica, Primerica affiliates and other Representatives;  

  * Financial services providers, such as companies engaged in banking, consumer finance, securities and insurance; and  

  * Non-financial companies, such as companies engaged in direct marketing, retailing and the selling of customer products and services.  

We may also disclose nonpublic personal information about you to nonaffiliated third parties as permitted by law.

IV. How to Opt Out of Information Disclosure  
We are committed to informing you about new products that may be useful to you and sharing information helps us do this. However, if you prefer that we not share personal information, you may request that we not share that personal information (that is, to “opt out” of sharing), except to the extent sharing is permitted by law.   

To opt out, please fill out and return the “Opt Out Form for Primerica and Its Independent Primerica Representatives” in this pamphlet. Your request to opt out of this Notice or the attached notice from the Primerica companies will result in your opting out under both notices. If you jointly obtain a Primerica product with others, your opt out request will also apply to them.  

Your request will remain in effect until you notify us otherwise in writing. If you have opted out previously, you need not do so again.
